questions:
  - id: add-cmds-q1
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Create an alias 'k' for 'kubectl'"
    response: "alias k=kubectl"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=You%20can%20also%20use%20a,that%20also%20works%20with%20completion"
  - id: add-cmds-q2
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Enable kubectl autocompletion for bash"
    response: "source <(kubectl completion bash)"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=BASH"
  - id: add-cmds-q3
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Add kubectl autocompletion to ~/.bashrc"
    response: "echo \"source <(kubectl completion bash)\" >> ~/.bashrc"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=source%20%3C%28kubectl%20completion%20bash%29%20,permanently%20to%20your%20bash%20shell"
  - id: add-cmds-q4
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Set the KUBECONFIG environment variable to /home/user/config"
    response: "export KUBECONFIG=/home/user/config"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/pt-br/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=Define%20com%20qual%20cluster%20Kubernetes,detalhadas%20do%20arquivo%20de%20configura%C3%A7%C3%A3o"
  - id: add-cmds-q5
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Check the kubectl client and server versions"
    response: "kubectl version"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,on%20the%20client%20and%20server"
  - id: add-cmds-q6
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Create a namespace named dev"
    response: "kubectl create namespace dev"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/generated/kubectl_create/kubectl_create_namespace/#:~:text=,namespace"
  - id: add-cmds-q7
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "List all namespaces"
    response: "kubectl get namespaces"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/administer-cluster/namespaces/#:~:text=Viewing%20namespaces"
  - id: add-cmds-q8
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Describe namespace dev"
    response: "kubectl describe namespace dev"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/administer-cluster/namespaces/#:~:text=You%20can%20also%20get%20the,of%20a%20specific%20namespace%20using"
  - id: add-cmds-q9
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Delete namespace dev"
    response: "kubectl delete namespace dev"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/administer-cluster/namespaces/#:~:text=Delete%20a%20namespace%20with"
  - id: add-cmds-q10
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Create a deployment named frontend using image nginx:1.14"
    response: "kubectl create deployment frontend --image=nginx:1.14"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/generated/kubectl_create/kubectl_create_deployment/#:~:text=,image%3Dbusybox"
  - id: add-cmds-q11
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "List all deployments"
    response: "kubectl get deployments"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=kubectl%20get%20pods%20,all%20pods%20in%20the%20namespace"
  - id: add-cmds-q12
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Describe deployment frontend"
    response: "kubectl describe deployment frontend"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/controllers/deployment/#:~:text=3,the%20Deployment"
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/controllers/deployment/#:~:text=Labels%3A%20%20%20%20,0"
  - id: add-cmds-q13
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Scale deployment frontend to 3 replicas"
    response: "kubectl scale deployment frontend --replicas=3"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/controllers/deployment/#:~:text=You%20can%20scale%20a%20Deployment,by%20using%20the%20following%20command"
  - id: add-cmds-q14
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Roll back the deployment frontend to the previous version"
    response: "kubectl rollout undo deployment frontend"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/controllers/deployment/#:~:text=1,rollback%20to%20the%20previous%20revision"
  - id: add-cmds-q15
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Restart the deployment frontend"
    response: "kubectl rollout restart deployment frontend"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=kubectl%20set%20image%20deployment%2Ffrontend%20www%3Dimage%3Av2,Xem%20tr%E1%BA%A1ng"
  - id: add-cmds-q16
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Delete deployment frontend"
    response: "kubectl delete deployment frontend"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/controllers/deployment/#:~:text=The%20output%20is%20similar%20to,this"
  - id: add-cmds-q17
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Run a pod named busybox with image busybox that runs indefinitely"
    response: "kubectl run busybox --image=busybox --restart=Never -- /bin/sh -c \"sleep 3600\""
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/generated/kubectl_run/#:~:text=,restart%3DNever"
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/generated/kubectl_run/#:~:text=,argN)"
  - id: add-cmds-q18
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "List all pods"
    response: "kubectl get pods"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=kubectl%20get%20pods%20,all%20pods%20in%20the%20namespace"
  - id: add-cmds-q19
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Describe pod busybox"
    response: "kubectl describe pod busybox"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=,pod)"
  - id: add-cmds-q20
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Delete pod busybox"
    response: "kubectl delete pod busybox"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=cat%20pod.json%20,JSON%20%C4%91%C6%B0%E1%BB%A3c%20truy%E1%BB%81n%20v%C3%A0o%20std"
  - id: add-cmds-q21
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Expose deployment frontend on port 80 as a ClusterIP service named frontend-svc"
    response: "kubectl expose deployment frontend --port=80 --type=ClusterIP --name=frontend-svc"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=,port%3D8000"
  - id: add-cmds-q22
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "List all services"
    response: "kubectl get services"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=,current%20namespace%2C%20with%20more%20details"
  - id: add-cmds-q23
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Describe service frontend-svc"
    response: "kubectl describe service frontend-svc"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=,pod)"
  - id: add-cmds-q24
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Delete service frontend-svc"
    response: "kubectl delete service frontend-svc"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=,port%3D8000"
  - id: add-cmds-q25
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Create a ConfigMap named app-config from file config.yaml"
    response: "kubectl create configmap app-config --from-file=config.yaml"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=files%3A%20"
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=)"
  - id: add-cmds-q26
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "List all ConfigMaps"
    response: "kubectl get configmaps"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Endpoints"
  - id: add-cmds-q27
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Describe configmap app-config"
    response: "kubectl describe configmap app-config"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=Define%20container%20environment%20variables%20using,ConfigMap%20data"
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=pods%2Fpod,to%20clipboard"
  - id: add-cmds-q28
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Delete configmap app-config"
    response: "kubectl delete configmap app-config"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=Before%20proceeding%2C%20clean%20up%20some,of%20the%20ConfigMaps%20you%20made"
  - id: add-cmds-q29
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Create a generic secret named db-secret with literal username and password"
    response: "kubectl create secret generic db-secret --from-literal=username=admin --from-literal=password=secret"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=1,value%20pair%20in%20a%20ConfigMap"
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=,you%20want%20to%20assign%20to"
  - id: add-cmds-q30
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "List all secrets"
    response: "kubectl get secrets"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Service"
  - id: add-cmds-q31
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Describe secret db-secret"
    response: "kubectl describe secret db-secret"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configmap-secret/managing-secret-using-config-file/#:~:text=Managing%20Secrets%20using%20Configuration%20File,yaml"
  - id: add-cmds-q32
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Delete secret db-secret"
    response: "kubectl delete secret db-secret"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=kubectl%20label%20pods%20my,T%E1%BB%B1%20%C4%91%E1%BB%99ng"
  - id: add-cmds-q33
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Create a ServiceAccount named default-sa"
    response: "kubectl create serviceaccount default-sa"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Service"
  - id: add-cmds-q34
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "List all ServiceAccounts"
    response: "kubectl get serviceaccounts"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Service"
  - id: add-cmds-q35
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Describe serviceaccount default-sa"
    response: "kubectl describe serviceaccount default-sa"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/configure-pod-configmap/#:~:text=,you%20want%20to%20assign%20to"
  - id: add-cmds-q36
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Delete serviceaccount default-sa"
    response: "kubectl delete serviceaccount default-sa"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Service"
  - id: add-cmds-q37
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Label pod busybox with env=prod"
    response: "kubectl label pod busybox env=prod"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=kubectl%20replace%20"
  - id: add-cmds-q38
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Remove the label env from pod busybox"
    response: "kubectl label pod busybox env-"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=kubectl%20replace%20"
  - id: add-cmds-q39
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Annotate deployment frontend with description=test"
    response: "kubectl annotate deployment frontend description=test"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=kubectl%20replace%20"
  - id: add-cmds-q40
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Remove the annotation description from deployment frontend"
    response: "kubectl annotate deployment frontend description-"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/vi/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=kubectl%20label%20pods%20my,T%E1%BB%B1%20%C4%91%E1%BB%99ng"
  - id: add-cmds-q41
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Apply the configuration in deployment.yaml"
    response: "kubectl apply -f deployment.yaml"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/pt-br/docs/reference/kubectl/cheatsheet/#:~:text=Manifestos%20Kubernetes%20podem%20ser%20definidos,podem%20ser%20usadas"
  - id: add-cmds-q42
    category: "Additional Commands"
    prompt: "Use kubectl to edit deployment frontend"
    response: "kubectl edit deployment frontend"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/controllers/deployment/#:~:text=3,the%20Deployment"
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/controllers/deployment/#:~:text=Labels%3A%20%20%20%20,0"
